RG 004:164, Windsor Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Windsor Probate Court records
1847-1977
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Windsor District)
118 cubic feet
Record books, 1855-1953; Probate files, 1847-1977, bulk 1855-1976.
RG004_164
2011-034, 2012-012
Historical Note
Windsor, Hartford County, Town settled 1633, named 1637
The Windsor Probate District was constituted July 4, 1855, from the Hartford Probate District. The Windsor Probate District merged with the East Windsor Probate District to create the Region #4 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Windsor, South Windsor, and Windsor.
Town of Windsor, Probate District chronology:
1633 - July 3, 1855, Hartford District
1649 - 1677, Particular Court Records
May 1759 - May 1768, Stafford District (covered Ellington Parish until it was set off with the Town of East Windsor in 1768)
July 4, 1855 - January 4, 2011 Windsor District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region #4 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, vol. 1-36, 1855-1952. Contact the probate court to access original record books numbered after 36. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1847-1977, bulk 1855-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2012-012 are numbered 1-35. There are two volumes numbered 1.
Probate files in accession 2011-034 are arranged roughly alphabetically in two A-Z sequences. The first sequence spans 1847-1975, bulk 1855-1975, and the second sequence spans 1863-1977, bulk 1931-1976.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the files in accession 2011-034.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Windsor
Places:
Windsor (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2012-012, Record books, 1855-1952, and Accession 2011-034, Probate files, 1847-1977, bulk 1855-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1946 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, vol. 1, 2, 4, 6, 9, 15, 1847-1916, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 2011-034 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 19, 2010, December 30, 2010, and December 9, 2011.
The record books in accession 2012-012 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 9, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1855-1953; 18 cubic feet (36 volumes); 2012-012
  - Wills & distributions of estates, 1857-1881 (Volume 1)
  - Orders and decrees, 1855-1871 (Volume 1)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Wills, inventories, etc., 1855-1870, 1897 (Volume 2)
  - Orders and decrees, 1870-1885 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1870-1889, 1898, 1908 (Volume 4)
  - Orders and decrees, 1885-1894 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1889-1897 (Volume 6)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Applications and returns, 1892-1911 (Volume 7)
  - Orders and decrees, 1894-1901 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1897-1904 (Volume 9)
  - Orders and decrees, 1902-1909 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1904-1911 (Volume 11)
  - Bonds, 1906-1935 (Volume 12)
  - Orders and decrees, 1909-1917 (Volume 13)
  - Applications and returns, 1910-1924 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1911-1916 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1916-1919 (Volume 16)
  - Orders and decrees, 1917-1922 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1919-1922 (Volume 18)
  - Orders and decrees, 1922-1927 (Volume 19)
  - Applications and returns, 1922-1929 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1921-1922 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1925-1927 (Volume 22)
  - Orders and decrees, 1927-1932 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1927-1930 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1930-1932 (Volume 25)
  - Applications and returns, 1931-1942 (Volume 26)
  - Orders and decrees, 1932-1937 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1932-1934 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1934-1936 (Volume 29)
  - Bonds, 1936-1953 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1936-1937 (Volume 31)
  - Orders and decrees, 1937-1941 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1937-1939 (Volume 33)
  - Applications and returns, 1938-1952 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1939-1948 (Volume 35)
- Probate files, 1847-1977, bulk 1855-1976; 100 cubic feet; 2011-034
  Arranged into two alphabetic sequences as received from Probate Court. The first sequence spans 1847-1975, bulk 1855-1975, and the second sequence spans 1863-1977, bulk 1931-1976.
  - Abbott - Barker (Box 1)
  - Barnard - Billings, R. (Box 2)
  - Billings, W. - Brown, Allison (Box 3)
  - Brown, Allison - Case, H. (Box 4)
  - Case, J. - Cobb, E. (Box 5)
  - Cobb, H. - Darcy (Box 6)
  - Darling - Drake (Box 7)
  - Drew - Filley, Julia (Box 8)
  - Filley, Joseph - Garvan (Box 9)
  - Gatchell - Griswold (Box 10)
  - Gruodis - Hayden, Lucinda (Box 11)
  - Hayden, Lucretia - Holcomb (Box 12)
  - Holden - Johnson, Keith (Box 13)
  - Johnson, Mary - LaFluer (Box 14)
  - Laflin - Loomer, C. (Box 15)
  - Loomer, F. - Mack (Box 16)
  - Mackey - Maude, H. (Box 17)
  - Maude, N. - Mills (Box 18)
  - Miner - Niles (Box 19)
  - Noble - Paulouskis (Box 20)
  - Paul - Pilifka (Box 21)
  - Pillsbury - Reynolds (Box 22)
  - Rengerman - Schindelholz (Box 23)
  - Schmidt - Solek (Box 24)
  - Soloshun - Taylor (Box 25)
  - Tatro - Voto (Box 26)
  - Vromont - Wilson, R. (Box 27)
  - Wilson, S. - Zukowski (Box 28)
  - Abbey - Allen, L. (Box 29)
  - Allen, M. - Bailey, E. (Box 30)
  - Bailey, G. - Barnes, M. (Box 31)
  - Barnes, R. - Beebe (Box 32)
  - Beeman - Billings, L. (Box 33)
  - Billings, R. - Bousquet (Box 34)
  - Bourdo - Brown, L. (Box 35)
  - Brown, M. - Busch (Box 36)
  - Busel - Carmody (Box 37)
  - Carmon - Chamberlin, C. (Box 38)
  - Chamberlin, E. - Clapp, E. (Box 39)
  - Clapp, G. - Cohon (Box 40)
  - Cole - Cranouski, P. (Box 41)
  - Cranouski, W. - Danno (Box 42)
  - Darack - Didno (Box 43)
  - Dickinson - Dower (Box 44)
  - Downey - Eagleson, G. (Box 45)
  - Eagleson, J. - Evans, James (Box 46)
  - Evans, Joseph - Feldman, M. (Box 47)
  - Feldman, S. - Flynt (Box 48)
  - Fogg - Fusco, T. (Box 49)
  - Fusco, G. - Gaylord (Box 50)
  - Gazik - Gonzalez (Box 51)
  - Goodale - Griffing (Box 52)
  - Griggs - Hagarty (Box 53)
  - Haggett - Harrison (Box 54)
  - Hart - Hemphill (Box 55)
  - Henault - Holcomb (Box 56)
  - Holcombe, A. - Holcombe, Oliver (Box 57)
  - Holcombe, Oliver - Hube, E. (Box 58)
  - Hube, F. - Jakobek, Martin (Box 59)
  - Jakobek, Mary - Jones, A. (Box 60)
  - Jones, B. - Keenan (Box 61)
  - Kegel - Kissouth, H. (Box 62)
  - Kissouth, S. - Lachapelle (Box 63)
  - Kuraitis - Lee (Box 64)
  - Leek - Linsley, Selden (Box 65)
  - Linsley, Selden - Luddy, A. (Box 66)
  - Luddy, J. - Mackie (Box 67)
  - Maddaluno - Marshall, A. (Box 68)
  - Marshall, E. - Maude (Box 69)
  - Maynard - McLaughlin (Box 70)
  - McLeod - Mills, Candace (Box 71)
  - Mills, Catherine - Moore (Box 72)
  - Moran - Nadler (Box 73)
  - Nagle - Nordberg (Box 74)
  - Norman - O'Leary, James (Box 75)
  - O'Leary, John - Paradis (Box 76)
  - Parente - Peck (Box 77)
  - Peichert - Phelphs, Maria (Box 78)
  - Phelps, Mary - Porter (Box 79)
  - Porteus - Quinn (Box 80)
  - Raleigh - Redfield (Box 81)
  - Reed - Root (Box 82)
  - Rooney - Sador (Box 83)
  - Sadowsky - Schmidt (Box 84)
  - Schillinger - Sheriden (Box 85)
  - Sherluck - Slavkin (Box 86)
  - Sledjeski - Snider, H. (Box 87)
  - Snider, W. - Starinovich (Box 88)
  - Starkel - Stromberg (Box 89)
  - Strong - Szlyjka (Box 90)
  - Szomatouski - Tibbetts (Box 91)
  - Tiffany - Tumillo (Box 92)
  - Turgeon - Urgo (Box 93)
  - Uricchio - Warner (Box 94)
  - Wasilauskas - Wheeler (Box 95)
  - Whipple - Willcox (Box 96)
  - Williams - Witkins (Box 97)
  - Witkowski - Wright (Box 98)
  - Wrisley - Zagrodnick (Box 99)
  - Zajac - Zutkowski (Box 100)
    Box 100 contains 59 additional files for surnames ranging from Anton to Young.